这是二零二五年河北省初中学业水平考试英语试卷听力部分。
听力部分共有。
四节，第一节至第三节为选择题，
第四节为填空题。
做题时，先将答案答在试卷上，在听力测试结束后，再将答案填涂到答题
卡上。
现在是听。
test time. Excuse me,
but could you tell me how to get to the cinema?
Which cinema? The Capitol Cinema.
Oh, it's a long way from here.
It better take a bus.
Which bus shall I take then?
I think you need to take number seven.
Thanks a lot.
You're welcome. B, and
试音到此结束。
第一节，听句子，选择最佳答语。
下面你将听到五个句子，每个句子读两遍，请你听完句子的第二遍。
读后，从每小题所给出的
三个选项中选出该句的最佳答语。
Number one. How are you, Tina?
How are you, Tina?
Number two. Which is your pet dog, Mike?
Which is your pet dog, Mike?
Number three. Tom, shall we go to Xibai Po this summer holiday?
Tom, shall we go to Xibai Po this summer holiday?
Number four. Mom, what will we have for
Mom, what will we have for supper?
Number five. Do you think kids should do some housework?
Do you think kids should do some housework?
kids should housework?
第二节：听对话和问题，选择正确答案。
下面你将听到六组对话和十三个问题，
每组对话和问题读两遍，请你听完。
对话和问题的第二遍朗读后，
根据所听内容，从每小题所给出的
三个选项中选出正确答案。
请听第一组对话，回答第六小题。
question. Listen to
Wow, a new watch!
Thank you, Cindy!
number six. does Cindy give to Peter?
What does Cindy give to Peter?
请听第二组对话，回答第七小题。
It's time for bed.
Let's turn off the TV.
Ten more minutes, please, Mom.
The match is finishing soon.
All right. It's time for bed.
Let's turn off the TV.
Ten more minutes, please, Mom.
The match is soon.
All right. Question number seven.
Where are the Where are the speakers?
请听第三组对话，回答第八九。
小题。
questions. Can you help me, Nancy?
Sure, Dad. I'm repairing the chair.
I need to change the broken leg.
What can I do?
Pass me the stick, please.
Here you are.
Let me hold the chair.
Thanks, but be careful.
I will, Dad.
Can you help me, Nancy?
Sure, Dad. I'm repairing the chair.
I need to change the broken leg.
What can I do?
Pass me the stick, please.
Here you are.
Let me hold the chair.
Thanks, but be careful.
I will, Dad.
Question number eight.
What is Nancy's dad repairing?
Question number nine.
What does Nancy pass her dad?
请听第四组对话，回答第十至十二小题。
What's in your hand, Tony?
A picture. What a nice picture!
Is that you on the bike?
Yes, I enjoy riding a bike.
It's a great sport.
Do you join in bike races a lot?
Yes, I just took part in a short bike race last month.
How many kilometers was it?
It was 30 kilometers.
Oh, that's not a short race.
Have you ever won any prizes?
No, never. I join in bike races just for fun, not for a prize.
What's in your hand, Tony?
A picture. What a nice picture!
Is that you on the bike?
Yes, I enjoy riding a bike.
It's a great sport.
Do you join in bike races a lot?
Yes, I just took part in a short bike race last month.
How many kilometers was it?
It was 30 kilometers.
Oh, that's not a short race.
Have you ever won any prizes?
No, never. I join in bike races just for fun, not for a prize.
Question number 10.
What is in Tony's hand?
Question number 11.
How many kilometers was the bike race last month?
Question number 12.
Why does Tony join in bike races?
请听第五组对话，回答第十三至十五小题。
It's so cold today.
Yes, it's snowing heavily.
Would you like a hot tea or coffee, John?
Tea, please. Thanks, Helen.
And we need to wear thick clothes this afternoon.
Oh, I'll wear a sweater.
It's really cold.
Yeah, I'll put on my new coat.
It's nice and warm.
It's so cold today.
Yes, it's snowing heavily.
Would you like a hot tea or coffee, John?
Tea, please. Thanks, Helen.
And we need to wear thick clothes this afternoon.
Oh, I'll wear a sweater.
It's really cold.
Yeah, I'll put on my new coat.
It's nice and warm.
number 13. How is the weather today?
Question number 14.
What does John drink?
Question number 15.
What will Helen wear this afternoon?
请听第六组对话，回答第十六至十八小题。
Hey, Mary, where did you go last weekend?
I went to Qinhuangdao with my family.
That's a good place.
How did you get there?
By train. How long did it take?
About two hours.
Oh, it's not far.
Yes, and we enjoyed ourselves on the beach.
What did you do there?
My family had a picnic.
Sounds good. My dad and I flew kites.
My brother picked up some beautiful stones.
And my mom took many photos.
Oh, wonderful. I hope to go there next weekend.
Hey, Mary, where did you go last weekend?
I went to Qinhuangdao with my family.
That's a good place.
How did you get there?
By train. How long did it take?
About two hours.
Oh, it's not far.
Yes, and we enjoyed ourselves on the beach.
What did you do there?
My family had a picnic.
Sounds good. My dad and I flew kites.
My brother picked up some beautiful stones.
And my mom took many photos.
Oh, wonderful. I hope to go there next weekend.
Question number 16.
How did Mary's family get to Qinhuangdao?
Question number 17.
How long did it take the family to get to Qinhuangdao?
Question number 18.
What did Mary and her dad do on the beach?
章节：听短文和问题，选择正确答案。
下面你将听到两篇短文和七个问题，
每篇短文和问题读两遍。
请你听完短文和问题的第二遍朗读后，
Qinhuangdao? dad the did do What do Hello, boys and girls.
根据所听内容。
从每小题所给出的
三个选项中选出正确答案。
请听第一篇短文，回答第十九至二十一小题。
Our school will start a chess club.
It will begin next Friday.
I think it will make your school life more colorful.
The club members will meet in the meeting room at 4.50 in the afternoon.
You will learn some skills and play chess games with players from other classes.
Some parents will come and offer help.
If you want to join a please let me know before the weekend.
Hello, boys and girls.
Our school will start a chess club.
It will begin next Friday.
I think it will make your school life more colorful.
The club members will meet in the meeting room at 4.50 in the afternoon.
You will learn some skills and play chess games with players from other classes.
Some parents will come and offer help.
If you want to join the please let me know before the weekend.
Question number 19.
What club will the school start?
Question number 20.
Where will the club members meet?
Question number 21.
Who will offer help in the club?
请听第二篇短文，回答第二十二至二十五小题。
Good morning, young listeners.
My name is Wang Jun.
I'm so happy to tell my story to you.
When I was in middle school, Mrs.
my art teacher, found my talent for painting.
She introduced many famous paintings to me and hoped I could be a
From then on, I got crazy about painting.
Mrs. Liu advised me to paint from nature.
On school days, I often painted by the river near my school.
After years of hard work, I became a painter.
I've painted more than 300 paintings.
People in many countries love my works.
I plan to hold an art show in my middle school in July, and I've got everything
ready for it.
Would you like to come?
morning, young listeners.
My name is Wang Jun.
I'm so happy to tell my story to you.
When I was in middle school, Mrs.
my art teacher, found my talent for painting.
She introduced many famous paintings to me and hoped I could be a painter.
From then on, I got crazy about painting.
Mrs. advised me to paint from nature.
On school days, I often painted by the river near my school.
After years of hard work, I became a painter.
I've painted more than 300 paintings.
People in many countries love my works.
I plan to hold an art show in my middle school in July, and I've got everything
ready for it.
Would you like to come?
number 22. What is Wang Jun doing?
What is Wang doing?
Question number 23.
Who found Wang Jun's talent for painting?
Question number 24.
Where did Wang Jun often paint on school
Where did Wang Jun often paint on school days?
Question number 25.
When will Wang Jun hold an art show?
number 26. Question number 38.
节听短文填空。
下面你将听到一篇短文，短文读两遍。
请你听完短文的第二遍朗读后，根据短文的内容和提示，在信息表中相应
的横线上填入所缺信息。
Question Question Question Question Question Our group task is shopping.
We'll act it out in class tomorrow.
You know, there are five members in our group,
and everybody will take part in the role play.
We'll use a big card to do the play.
Please look at the pictures of fruits on the card.
Jan, you sell the fruits on it, and the rest of us choose anything on it to buy.
Now I'll talk about the rules for us to follow.
We must speak English and express ourselves in a polite way.
Okay, let's start to practice.
Hi, everyone. Attention, please.
I'd like to say something about the role play.
Our group task is shopping.
We'll act it out in class tomorrow.
You know, there are five members in our group, and everybody will take part in the
role play. We'll use a big card to do the play.
Please look at the pictures of fruits on the card.
Jan, you sell the fruits on it, and the rest of us choose anything on it to buy.
Now I'll talk about the rules for us to follow.
We must speak English and express ourselves in a polite way.
Okay, let's start to
The
听力部分到此结束，预祝同学们取得好成绩。